# **Everton Canez**

evcanez@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/everton-canez

## Summary

I'm a flexible easy going style with 18y+ hands-on software development experience and practical experience in web and mobile projects.

I like frontend and backend development, I love programming languages and I'm very committed self-learning person.

I have experience working in many teams and I have good communication skills. For the last 9 years I've been working with JavaScript; Typescript; AngularJS; Restify; Express; NodeJS; Angular 2, 3, 4, 5...; UX; Ionic; Cordova; Progressive Web Apps; RESTful APIs; Java; Android; OOP; Micro-services and PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL and Oracle Databases.

You can read my full resumé and portfolio right here: https://notreniev.github.io/resume/

## **Experience**



### **Full Stack Developer**

Sep 2019- Present

Hotmedia - Web Broadcast Radio & Television

3 months +

Responsible for frontend and backend development in Angular and NodeJS. Also implementing automation tests using Jest and CI/CD deploy on GitLab.



#### **Full Stack Developer**

Aug 2011- Present

**PROCERGS** 

8 years 4 months +

In 2011 I did for a public tender to start at a new position as Java Analyst and I passed to assume a new position. I started working with Java/PHP/Javascript/HTML/CSS in several intern projects to solve problems for the management area who wanted to automatize some processes and workflows in the company using Oracle Workflow and Java.

Some of these workflows were about the implementation of ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library), in disciplines like Configuration Management, Changing Management, Problems Management and so on.



### **Technical Operations Engineer**

Feb 2005 - Aug 2010

**PROCERGS** 

5 years 7 months

In 2005 I was invited to join the Technical Operations Team. At this point, I was beginning with Java/JSP for software development in one project, but in the Technical Operations team I was able to work in several other projects. In some point I was responsible for maintaining 6 Java applications simultaneously, all of them communicating with each other via web services (SOAP and after a while RESTful).

By the time it was a common thing the monolithic architecture and so it was for a while. Meanwhile, I was having a good progression on my career being promoted each couple of years or so.

**Technical Specialist** 

Mar 2000 - Jan 2005

**PROCERGS** 

4 years 11 months

In March 2000, I became a team member of the Systems Operations Department as a Technical Specialist and I was responsible for developing web systems for the company's intranet. By then I used to program a lot in ASP and had to learn more about data modeling and some Systems Analysis, providing a huge workflow for this department I was working in.



### **System Network Administrator**

Aug 1998 - Jul 2001

Colégio Marista Nossa Senhora do Rosário

3 years

Responsible for the administration of school's intranet, network, support and website development.



### **Call Center Agent**

Dec 1997 - Mar 2000

PROCERGS 2 years 4 months

Call center attendant responsible for give support for the clients of several areas like Police Department, Public Security, Water and Sewage Department and Company's Internet Provider clients.

#### **Education**



#### Universidade de Santa Cruz do Sul

2014 - 2016

Graduate Course, Computer Software Engineering, Software Engineering for Government Solutions

Software Engineering with Emphasis on Government Solutions



### **Technology University SenacRS**

2007 - 2010

Degree in Information Systems, Computer Software Technologyst

Analysis and Software Development in Information Systems.

#### **Skills**



JavaScript • Web Services • Java • Mobile Applications • Web Development